

### VINCENT G MUKOMBA DATA ANALYSTIDATA SCIENTIST

- Parklands, Cape Town, Western Cape
- mukombav@gmail.com
- +27714110778
- https://github.com/Vincemcomber
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/vincent-mukomba-113b3615b/

Visa Status: Permanent Residence Permit

\* Willing to relocate

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Vincent is an aspiring data analyst/scientist and a Data Science Bootcamp graduate at HyperionDev with six months of work experience in IT industry and more than three years of working experience in the finance industry. Highly skilled in data analysis, data science, python, machine learning and exploratory data analysis. I have a great passion for turning data into insights that help businesses make better decisions.

### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

#### DATA SCIENCE BOOTCAMP

• HyperionDev, Nov 2022 - May 2023

### Link: <a href="https://www.hyperiondev.com/portfoli">https://www.hyperiondev.com/portfoli</a> o/108166/

**PROJECTS** 

#### PYTHON:

- taskManager.py to help small business manage tasks.
- **inventory.py** to help businesses on stock management.

#### DATA ANALYTICS AND EXPLORATION

- **ebookstore.py** Modified to using database and SQL.
- Hotel\_booking\_analysis.ipynb perform EDA of given hotel bookings dataset.
- EDA on Vedio Games sales perform an EDA on video games dataset.

#### **MACHINE LEARNING:**

- Mnist\_task.ipynb using Linear, Multi-Linear and Logistics regressions, and Decisions Trees to train, predict, and plot results.
- US-Arrests-KMeans-Agglomerative-Dendrograms.ipynb Using the US Arrests dataset applying EDA, Principal Component Analysis, 2 clustering techniques KMeans & Agglomerative Clustering with Dendogrograms.

#### **BACHELOR OF ECONOMICS WITH HONOURS**

• Rhodes University, Feb 2015 - Dec 2015

#### **BACHELOR OF ECONOMICS**

• Rhodes University, Feb 2012- Dec 2014

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### DATA ANALYST (FREELANCE)

**HyperionDev** 

Nov 2022 - May 2023

- Created a project management system that help small businesses on stock management.
- Initiated a python project to help small business manage tasks.
- Spearheaded and modified a database program, using database and SQL, used by a bookstore clerks to add/remove new/sold books and run a bookstore shop.
- Managed to use different machine learning models to analyse and visualize data to develop actionable strategic insights and innovative solutions for decision-making.

#### FINANCIAL PLANNER

Hereford Group

Feb 2022 - May 2022

- Contacted clients and set up meetings, either within an office environment or in clients' homes or business premises to sell that meet their targets.
- Completed risk analysis, designed financial strategies, reviewed and responded to clients changing needs and financial circumstances that led to a 4% increase in the sale of products.

#### ASSISTANT FINANCIAL OFFICER

RoyalG Holdingd Pty Ltd

Mar 2018 - Dec 2020

- Collaborated with the team to implement financial policies, which ultimately reduced unnecessary expenditure and losses by 50% and resulted in a positive financial audit.
- Part of the team that advised the company on economic decisions resulting in a 10% increase in productivity.
- Implemented disaster recovery plans in line with the business continuity requirements and ensured 99.9% business availability.

#### JUNIOR FINANCE OFFICER (INTERNSHIP)

Black Star Security Services Jan 20

Jan 2016 -- Feb 2018

- Ensured optimum cash operating cycle by careful control of creditors, debtors and stock which led to a reduction in costs by an average of R70 000 per year.
- Guaranteed that all projects were delivered on time, within scope and within budget that led a 7% increase in income.
- Ensured that resources were available and allocated efficiently which resulted in a 6% growth of the company.

# ADDITIONAL VOLUNTARY WORK EXPERIENCE

**Rhodes University** 

2013, 2015

- First years Economics Tutor, Feb 2015 Nov 2015.
- Grade 12 Economics Tutor, Feb 2013 Oct 2013.

#### **TECH SKILLS**

- Data Analysis and Analytics
- Data Science
- Data Engineering
- Computer Science
- Machine Learning
- Artificial Intelligence
- Data Cleaning, Modelling and Visualization
- Predictive Analysis
- Exploratory Data Analysis
- Extract, Transform, and Load (ETL)
- Python
- Java
- Jupyter Notebook
- SQL and Databases Applications
- Microsoft Excel
- Power BI
- Tableau
- Tech Savvy and Technological Innovation
- Mathematics and Statistical Analysis
- Research Skills and Report writing

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

- · Attention to detail and resilient
- Work under pressure and passionate about work
- Collaboration and time management
- Teamwork,teaming and reciprocity
- Problem Solving and operational efficiency
- Adaptable and flexible
- Critical Thinking and Analytical skills
- Communication and interpersonal skills
- Innovative, performance and results driven
- Knowledge acquisition and skill development
- Defining Requirements and Workload Prioritization
- Organizational skills

## ADDITIONAL EDUCATION - SELF STUDY

- Introduction to Data Science, Alison Education, 2023.
- Microsoft Azure Data Fundamentals, Microsoft, 2023.
- Microsoft Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals, Microsoft, 2023.
- Advanced Google Analytics, Google, 2023.
- Google Analytics for Beginners, Google, 2023.
- Excel Skills for Data Analytics and Data Visualization, Coursera, 2023.
- Business Analytics, Coursera, 2023.
- IBM Data Science Professional Certificate, Coursera, 2023- in progress.

#### REFERENCES

· Available on Request